<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.4.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-10-15T10:27:05+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Terry Mafura</title><subtitle>I'm not a robot, I'm just like you</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Along came forloopZimbabwe</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/along-came-forloopZimbabwe/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Along came forloopZimbabwe" /><published>2019-05-13T09:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-05-13T09:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/along-came-forloopZimbabwe</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/along-came-forloopZimbabwe/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-new-chapter-from-southern-africa&quot;&gt;A new chapter from Southern Africa&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“There is no power for change greater than a community discovering what it cares about.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Margaret J. Wheatley&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Building a culture of community, learning to listen to each other, sharing knowledge and building together. A lot can be learnt from a group of people who have a hunger for knowledge, zeal for success and an appetite to represent the best of what can be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://forloopzim.co.zw&quot;&gt;forloopZimbabwe!!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;meet-share-collaborate&quot;&gt;Meet, Share, Collaborate&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/jaha-tribe/image/upload/v1567160451/maffsojah.co.zw/official_banner_fl5ikl.png&quot; alt=&quot;forloopZimbabwe Launch&quot; title=&quot;forloopZimbabwe Launch&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/forloopZimbabwe?src=hash&quot;&gt;#forloopZimbabwe&lt;/a&gt; Maiden event hosted on 13 April 2019 in Harare, Zimbabwe&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meet, Share, Collaborate grew from being a mere theme at the Maiden event of #forloopZimbabwe to becoming a code, a value, and a worthy cause in the Zimbabwean tech scene. It started with numerous discussions about the growth of Zim tech communities, the issues they have faced over the years and what solutions are available to fix these issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“…so you are good at JavaScript, he is good at social media marketing, she is an expert in Big Data. How can we help each other get good jobs, remote jobs or maybe build life changing projects?”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meeting(remotely or physically), Sharing(advice, knowledge, resources, even contacts) and Collaborating(building solutions, teaching other people). These became the core values of a growing community for #forloopZimbabwe. As a first event, the theme had to be inclusive, not too technical, and relating to the core values and goals of &lt;a href=&quot;https://forloop.africa/&quot;&gt;forloopAfrica&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-maiden-event&quot;&gt;the maiden event…&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/jaha-tribe/image/upload/v1567177302/maffsojah.co.zw/forloopzim_event_c3w9xr.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;forloopZimbabwe Event Attendees&quot; title=&quot;forloopZimbabwe Attendees&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/forloopZimbabwe?src=hash&quot;&gt;#forloopZimbabwe&lt;/a&gt; maiden event attendees April 13 2019— ImpactHub Harare&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If anyone had foretold the whole experience of organising the #forloopZimbabwe maiden event, I don’t think I would have agreed 😅. This experience became the most stressful and exciting thing I’ve done in 2019. The idea of getting many people together, networking, getting a venue, food among other things seemed like an impossible task until the day of the launch. It was a one-day event with 5 talks, unfortunately &lt;strong&gt;Olivier J.M&lt;/strong&gt; the 6th speaker from forloopZambia couldn’t make it to the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our speakers were from different fields of technology and this is what made their sessions interesting. Each talk had a Q&amp;amp;A session and a 15-minute break for networking because the main goal of the event was to meet different people who attended and find a common ground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-speakers&quot;&gt;The speakers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;brighton-mukorera--from-the-old-to-blockchain&quot;&gt;Brighton Mukorera – “From the old to blockchain”&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/jaha-tribe/image/upload/v1567178746/maffsojah.co.zw/brighton_lzktdf.png&quot; alt=&quot;Brighton Mukorera&quot; title=&quot;Brighton Mukorera -- From the old to blockchain&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brighton talked about making use of skills you have acquired from the basics of programming to become a blockchain developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow Brighton on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/bmukorera&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and checkout his &lt;a href=&quot;#&quot;&gt;Talk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;hannah-madzinga--putting-data-to-good-use&quot;&gt;Hannah Madzinga – “Putting data to good use”&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/jaha-tribe/image/upload/v1567178746/maffsojah.co.zw/hannah_knpn2y.png&quot; alt=&quot;Hannah Madzinga&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hannah talked about how we can leverage the data that’s already at our disposal for good use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow Hannah on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/HannahNMadzinga&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and checkout her &lt;a href=&quot;#&quot;&gt;Talk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;prosper-otemuyiwa--engineering-faster-web-experiences-in-plain-sight&quot;&gt;Prosper Otemuyiwa – “Engineering faster Web experiences in Plain Sight”&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/jaha-tribe/image/upload/v1567178746/maffsojah.co.zw/prosper_zhjryd.png&quot; alt=&quot;Prosper Otemuyiwa&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prosper talked about the instant to-do rules and optimal strategies to build fast loading web experiences for users from every region.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow Prosper on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/unicodeveloper&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and checkout his &lt;a href=&quot;#&quot;&gt;Talk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;shingirai-marandure--tech-collabo&quot;&gt;Shingirai Marandure – “Tech collabo”&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/jaha-tribe/image/upload/v1567178746/maffsojah.co.zw/shingie_kgj2qt.png&quot; alt=&quot;Shingirai Marandure&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shingirai encouraged collaboration on projects among developers and called for increased and improved participation of women in tech.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow Shingie on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/lassie034&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and checkout her &lt;a href=&quot;#&quot;&gt;Talk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;lennex-zinyando--remote-possible-how-to-work-from-the-jungle&quot;&gt;Lennex Zinyando – “Remote Possible: How to work from the jungle”&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/jaha-tribe/image/upload/v1567178746/maffsojah.co.zw/lennex_r4td2l.png&quot; alt=&quot;Lennex Zinyando&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lennex gave pointers on how to make the job hunting process less painful while making yourself a better developer that gets job offers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow Lennex on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/zinyando&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and checkout his &lt;a href=&quot;#&quot;&gt;Talk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-afternoonshow&quot;&gt;the AfternoonShow&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was an afternoon session for networking, asking questions and understanding the values that brought about the forloopAfrica community. This session had Prosper leading the discussion, answering different questions from the crowd while talking about the roots of forloopAfrica and what lies ahead for the community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He received various questions ranging from his skillset, forloopAfrica, women in tech, remote working and the crowd’s favorite comparison between Nigerian and Ghanain jollof(there is video evidence) 😂. He even went further to compare Nigerian jollof to Laravel code because of it’s presentation.
We also received some questions from those who were live-streaming the event on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-next&quot;&gt;what’s next?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The maiden event showed how much people love to work as a community, how curious people are when it comes to development’s best practices and their willingness to share and learn from each other. #forloopZimbabwe aims to put the Zimbabwean tech community on the world map while also collaborating with other forloopAfrica chapters in different countries. We believe we can grow from learning and also teaching others. This will be done through more events, bootcamps or hackathons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/jaha-tribe/image/upload/v1567179802/maffsojah.co.zw/selfie_pufeig.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;forloopZimbabwe Selfie&quot; title=&quot;forloopZimbabwe Selfie&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/unicodeveloper&quot;&gt;Prosper Otemuyiwa&lt;/a&gt; taking a group selfie&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;forloopZimbabwe&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; maiden event was made possible by Cloudinary and many more events can be made possible if we get sponsorship. The &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;forloopZimbabwe&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; sponsorship packages are available on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://forloopzim.co.zw&quot;&gt;forloopZimbabwe website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A special shout out to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/kenessarjr&quot;&gt;Remy Muhire&lt;/a&gt; for recommending us to start a forloopZimbabwe, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/unicodeveloper&quot;&gt;Prosper Otemuyiwa&lt;/a&gt; for helping us launch this wonderful community and flying to Zimbabwe for the event , &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/zinyando&quot;&gt;Lennex Zinyando&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/thedoer_&quot;&gt;Adonis Rumbwere&lt;/a&gt; for co-organising the event, all the speakers, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ImpactHubHarare&quot;&gt;ImpactHub Harare&lt;/a&gt; for hosting us, attendees and the wonderful people at &lt;a href=&quot;https://forloop.africa/&quot;&gt;forloopAfrica&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is because;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Alone, we can do so little; together, we can do so much.”&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Helen Keller&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;✌🏾&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>terrymafura</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="zimbabwe" /><category term="forloopZimbabwe" /><category term="forloopAfrica" /><summary type="html">A new chapter from Southern Africa</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/official_banner.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">100 Days of Code Challenge Days 11-20</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/100-Days-of-Code-Days-11-20/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="100 Days of Code Challenge Days 11-20" /><published>2017-08-04T23:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2017-08-04T23:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/100-Days-of-Code-Days-11-20</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/100-Days-of-Code-Days-11-20/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-11---august-04-2017&quot;&gt;Day 11 - August 04 2017&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;11-react-fundamentals&quot;&gt;[11] React Fundamentals&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;today was a very hectic day, too much work at the office and less code today.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I did spare some time to read about implicit binding, explicit binding and new and window binding using the &lt;strong&gt;this&lt;/strong&gt; keyword.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Day 11 yaaaaaaay :stuck_out_tongue_winking_eye:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-12---august-05-2017&quot;&gt;Day 12 - August 05 2017&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;12-react-fundamentals&quot;&gt;[12] React Fundamentals&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;learnt about new and window binding&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-13---august-06-2017&quot;&gt;Day 13 - August 06 2017&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;13-react-fundamentals&quot;&gt;[13] React Fundamentals&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;learnt about stateful and stateless functions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-14---august-07-2017&quot;&gt;Day 14 - August 07 2017&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;14-react-fundamentals&quot;&gt;[14] React Fundamentals&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;busy day at the office, didn’t even touch or see any code.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’m even dissappointed in myself but the body refused to do anything.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-15---august-08-2017&quot;&gt;Day 15 - August 08 2017&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;15-react-fundamentals&quot;&gt;[15] React Fundamentals&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;still too much work, was out of office but managed to squeeze in 30 minutes of writng some code.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Not really impressed but I guess I will be back to normal tomorrow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>terrymafura</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="100DaysOfCodeChallenge" /><summary type="html">Day 11 - August 04 2017 [11] React Fundamentals today was a very hectic day, too much work at the office and less code today. I did spare some time to read about implicit binding, explicit binding and new and window binding using the this keyword. Day 11 yaaaaaaay :stuck_out_tongue_winking_eye:</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/react.svg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">100 Days of Code Challenge Days 1-10</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/100-Days-of-Code-Days-1-10/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="100 Days of Code Challenge Days 1-10" /><published>2017-07-25T23:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2017-07-25T23:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/100-Days-of-Code-Days-1-10</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/100-Days-of-Code-Days-1-10/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-1---july-25-2017&quot;&gt;Day 1 - July 25 2017&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-project-manager-application-using-react-js&quot;&gt;[1] Project Manager application using React JS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;setup project, linked with Firebase, added Projects and Todo components, getting Todos from API&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Also started contributing to some awesome project &lt;em&gt;well, not really. haven’t started yet, but I’m in. I will post more about it. yaaay&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Link to the project &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/maffsojah/projectmanager&quot;&gt;Project Manager App&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-2---july-26-2017&quot;&gt;Day 2 - July 26 2017&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-project-manager-app-react&quot;&gt;[2] Project Manager App, React&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;today I decided to get back to the drawing board. I realised I had a lot to learn and since I have practised what I have learnt so far on a project, I decided to get back to reading.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On the &lt;em&gt;Project Manager&lt;/em&gt; App I decided to start with some new layout because it was just plain old JSX without any styles&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I got to learn about Component Validation using PropTypes, Authentication and building react for production.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Open Source Project&lt;/em&gt;  - I learnt a very huge lesson today, I realised I have a long way to go and I havent really grasped as much as I would expect to. I met people who were writing code I had never seen before, concepts I had never heard of before.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I will be good at this :stuck_out_tongue_winking_eye:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-3---july-27-2017&quot;&gt;Day 3 - July 27 2017&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-vanilla-js-react&quot;&gt;[3] Vanilla JS, React&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;today was a bit tricky. Besides trying to learn how I could contribute to an Open Source project, I was back at Vanilla JavaScript.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Most of the problems I am facing are merely caused by not fully grasping JavaScript (I intend to be a ninja though :stuck_out_tongue_winking_eye:)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I also learnt how to build react projects for production and how to deploy on now.sh, Github Pages and Apache server.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I was a bit tired today, didn’t feel like doing any coding. As I was writing this post, I thought about my favorite quote and I guess I will be staying up for another 3 hours.
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Decide that you want it more than you are afraid of it.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Unknown&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-4---july-28-2017&quot;&gt;Day 4 - July 28 2017&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;4-vanilla-js&quot;&gt;[4] Vanilla JS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;today was about getting up from the basics. I was reading about objects and arrays again.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;this will make sense in the next couple of days&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-5---july-29-2017&quot;&gt;Day 5 - July 29 2017&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;5-vanilla-js&quot;&gt;[5] Vanilla JS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I finished up freeCodeCamp Basic Javascript.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;started on the basic algorithm scripting with JavaScript&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-6---july-30-2017&quot;&gt;Day 6 - July 30 2017&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;6-freecodecamp&quot;&gt;[6] freeCodeCamp&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;learnt about JSON APIs and Ajax&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;started the intermediate Front End Development Projects&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I don’t really like Bootstrap so I have been learning materialize-css, it if a pretty cool framework.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-7---july-31-2017&quot;&gt;Day 7 - July 31 2017&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;7-react&quot;&gt;[7] React&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;since I decided to start refreshing my JS, I also started React again with React Fundamentals by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/tylermcginnis33&quot;&gt;Tyler Mcginnis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;this was after I learnt about uploading my react sites on now.sh, Github Pages, Apache Server and why I can eject my create-react-app&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the learning process is a bit jumbled up, this is because I figured I couldn’t finish courses if I got stuck on them for a long time.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I do feel tired, been a busy day at work but I realise I have to get at least an hour to learn code, learn JavaScript, learn React.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In the next few weeks I will get a lot busier at work and will be travelling too. My only hope is I don’t get tired with this process, I don’t lose hope in the process, I keep coding and coding until I am the ninja I wish to be.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I plan to not stop, I plan to finish these 100 Days and continue for more and I will do just that.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;:stuck_out_tongue_winking_eye:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-8---august-01-2017&quot;&gt;Day 8 - August 01 2017&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;8-react-fundamentals&quot;&gt;[8] React Fundamentals&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;learnt about Webpack, JavaScript Modules and Babel.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;focus was on how the stuff works in React and how to use them.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Today was one of the most productive days I’ve had on this process&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-9---august-02-2017&quot;&gt;Day 9 - August 02 2017&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;9-react-fundamentals&quot;&gt;[9] React Fundamentals&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;learnt about Dataflow with Props in React&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;building UIs with Pure Functions and Function Composition in React&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-10---august-03-2017&quot;&gt;Day 10 - August 03 2017&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;10-react-fundamentals&quot;&gt;[10] React Fundamentals&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;read about the multiple approaches of handling the &lt;strong&gt;this&lt;/strong&gt; keyword&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;since I started React,  have been binding in the constructor. I will continue doing this until I understand more about using Arrow functions in the class property.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Phew, the first 10 days. They felt like 20years woah!! I’m glad I’m getting used to it and learning a lot too :stuck_out_tongue_winking_eye:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>terrymafura</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="100DaysOfCodeChallenge" /><summary type="html">Day 1 - July 25 2017 [1] Project Manager application using React JS setup project, linked with Firebase, added Projects and Todo components, getting Todos from API Also started contributing to some awesome project well, not really. haven’t started yet, but I’m in. I will post more about it. yaaay</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/react.svg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">100 Days of Code Challenge Intro</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/100-Days-of-Code/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="100 Days of Code Challenge Intro" /><published>2017-07-25T18:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2017-07-25T18:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/100-Days-of-Code</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/100-Days-of-Code/">&lt;p&gt;I have decided to take part in the 100 Days of Code Challenge. I will be mainly focusing on learning JavaScript and famliarising myself with contributions to Open Source projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I  am so excited :stuck_out_tongue_winking_eye:&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>terrymafura</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="100DaysOfCodeChallenge" /><summary type="html">I have decided to take part in the 100 Days of Code Challenge. I will be mainly focusing on learning JavaScript and famliarising myself with contributions to Open Source projects.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">PyconZim 2016 Moments - part 2</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/attending-pyconzim-2/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="PyconZim 2016 Moments - part 2" /><published>2017-02-05T09:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2017-02-05T09:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/attending-pyconzim-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/attending-pyconzim-2/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-i-learnt-at-pyconzim&quot;&gt;What I learnt at PyconZim&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The previous post about PyconZim 2016 was just a meer display of excitement. I had to be excited, I met a lot of
cool people and learnt a lot too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-10-minute-intro-to-vim&quot;&gt;The 10-minute Intro to Vim&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vim Vim Vim!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-pycon-talks&quot;&gt;The Pycon talks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;310&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/fT21lXDErXk&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;figcaption class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Mike Place - Introduction to managing systems with SaltStack&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;breaker&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;310&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/iMF05VehKPE&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;figcaption class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Amanda Gelender - Social Impact &amp;amp; Open Source : How developers can drive change.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;breaker&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;310&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/cbBh87ebRzg&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;figcaption class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Ronald Maravanyika - Growing Python use among women&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;breaker&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;310&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/7WzRWdR6RZk&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;figcaption class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Tendai Marengereke - Reproducible Research in Python&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;breaker&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watch more PyconZim 2016 talks &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCUIWWO9HgKw3-tjrY0jeU_w&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>terrymafura</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="zimbabwe" /><category term="python programming" /><category term="PyconZim" /><summary type="html">What I learnt at PyconZim</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/pyconzim2016.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">PyconZim 2016 Moments - part 1</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/attending-pyconzim-1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="PyconZim 2016 Moments - part 1" /><published>2017-01-21T21:20:00+02:00</published><updated>2017-01-21T21:20:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/attending-pyconzim-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/attending-pyconzim-1/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;part-1&quot;&gt;Part 1…&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the 24th and 25th of November 2016, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/pycon_zim&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PyCon Zimbabwe&lt;/a&gt; hosted its first gathering in Harare, Zimbabwe. I was fortunate enough to attend the event
and it was the first tech conference I attended. I have attended a couple of tech gatherings, one hackathon and that’s it. This was an eye opener
for me and I really learnt a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-food&quot;&gt;the Food&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Food!!! my oh my, we can’t talks about a Tech conference/ event without mentioning the food. I goes without saying that these event really do their
most when it comes to the food. I enjoyed myself during break and lunch times,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-photos&quot;&gt;the photos&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5598/30673263763_c4e19fff41_z_d.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Markdowm Image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5605/31110610310_794cf6243d_z_d.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Markdowm Image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5618/31444484516_bcf2535ffa_z_d.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Markdowm Image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5473/30640244564_3806e4d5c7_z_d.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Markdowm Image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5580/30672912953_1e6c99f6af_z_d.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Markdowm Image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/99/31362889072_d899980777_z_d.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Markdowm Image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5587/31335278652_d85b0183f9_z_d.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Markdowm Image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5566/30640589064_509e150c40_z_d.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Markdowm Image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5597/31444598616_78bd5200bc_z_d.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Markdowm Image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5516/31365842801_b1ac56f018_z_d.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Markdowm Image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5550/31335015252_ca59000d9b_z_d.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Markdowm Image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5604/31365793891_fe03e9d38c_z_d.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Markdowm Image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/19/30700220333_b3de924fc7_z_d.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Markdowm Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>terrymafura</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="zimbabwe" /><category term="python programming" /><category term="PyconZim" /><summary type="html">Part 1…</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/pyconzim2016.jpg" /></entry></feed>